[{"id": "601370b51381754895396384", "question": "From where did the NHL St. Louis Blues obtain their name?", "answer": "The name is derived from musician\u00a0W.C. Handy\u2019s classic\u00a0composition\u00a0\"St. Louis Blues\".", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133922a", "question": "What Welsh songstress has performed the themes for three different Bond movies?", "answer": "Shirley Bassey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5be581c25415ba52ed6f0ac4", "question": "In the 1990 film \"Home Alone\", who played the roles of the robbers?", "answer": "Joe Pesci and Daniel Stern", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdfbe8e003d27d341092bd0", "question": "Why are Amsterdam's buildings so narrow?", "answer": "A tax loophole", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fef65b56ce05a3942286e70", "question": "Who is the Winslow family\u2019s nerdy neighbor in \"Family Matters\"", "answer": "Steve Urkel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a27e", "question": "In which 1989 film did Kevin Costner play the role of Ray Kinsella?", "answer": "Field of Dreams", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9e1", "question": "What birds were used by Japanese and Chinese fishermen to help catch fish?", "answer": "Cormorant", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae70", "question": "What US first lady was nicknamed \"the Silver Fox\"?", "answer": "Barbara Bush", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c944", "question": "Who invented the kinetoscope?", "answer": "Louis Le Prince", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea3d08ff048f679a45ab46", "question": "Tercel is the name for the male of which animal?", "answer": "Hawk", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ee4", "question": "Whose first big hit, \"Oh, Carol\", was about his ex-girlfriend Carole King?", "answer": "Neil Sedaka's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb86", "question": "What South African golfer is nicknamed \"The Big Easy\"?", "answer": "Ernie Els", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecdd21ec223966ae8f88ff", "question": "Who introduced Johnny Depp to acting?", "answer": "Nicolas Cage", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca5d", "question": "Which flower is also known as the \"Lent Lily\"?\u00a0", "answer": "The daffodil", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fbb", "question": "Who played the hominal robot, Ash, in the movie \"Alien\"?", "answer": "Ian Holm", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5990f3c7fa5fdd6dd25324dc", "question": "What's the principal river of Ireland?", "answer": "Shannon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5937ecd808d98002fdd633c1", "question": "What is an Ishihara Test used for?", "answer": "To check colour blindness", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339887", "question": "What colour did The Hulk originally start as?", "answer": "Grey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b23adf68f1a2238a7cb2b3a", "question": "In the novel series, \"A Series of Unfortunate Events\", who was the Baudelaire's sixth guardian?", "answer": "Jerome and Esme Squalor", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a91", "question": "What was Norm's last name on the TV show  \"Cheers\"?", "answer": "Peterson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015e318fe83fe1f2a824ba6", "question": "During the Battle of Midway, Japan lost what?", "answer": "Most of its aircraft carriers.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c02f", "question": "What type of food is Fontina?", "answer": "Cheese", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58bb34fee368446ca7bd684d", "question": "Which modern-day country is often considered as the birthplace of coffee?", "answer": "Ethiopia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea7e54ff048f679a45ac0b", "question": "A BTU refers to what?", "answer": "The amount of energy required to raise one pound of water one degree Fahrenheit", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2af", "question": "According to the title of the film, what is the profession of Ace Ventura?", "answer": "Pet Detective", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c937", "question": "Which is a small flightless bird, also New Zealand's national symbol?", "answer": "Kiwi", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015f031fe83fe1f2a824c10", "question": "The total number of years the Israelites spent in captivity is?", "answer": "430 -- The Israelite spent about 430 years in Egypt.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b17", "question": "What was the first name of Julia Roberts' character in the 2001 movie \"Ocean's Eleven\"?", "answer": "Tess", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7cca0877e98cb97778a28", "question": "What country would you have to visit to enjoy a taste of Hymettus honey?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7d3", "question": "The card game Patience is also known by what other name?", "answer": "Solitaire", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febb2667e83c707845b2112", "question": "Which celestial body is known as both the morning star and evening star?", "answer": "Venus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2d0", "question": "Who directed the 1956 film \"High Society\"?", "answer": "Charles Walters", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601debe96b1208747aa7e9d7", "question": "Which famous entrepreneur is credited with inventing the weekend?", "answer": "Henry Ford", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c60c", "question": "Entomologists study what?", "answer": "Insects", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5937ea1808d98002fdd6339f", "question": "Stephen King's \"The Shining\" is set at which hotel?", "answer": "Overlook Hotel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "597cd9d5e347d002c297e4cf", "question": "What became the tallest building in London after its official opening in October 1965?", "answer": "Post Office Tower", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fdd", "question": "Who was the Phoenician goddess of fertility, sexuality and war?", "answer": "Astarte", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fecc38eec223966ae8f887f", "question": "Who won the 1981 Grammy for \"Record of the Year\"?", "answer": "Christopher Cross for \"Sailing\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60062c98c9d816e292245c2d", "question": "What kind of cans did Andy Warhol famously paint?", "answer": "Campbell's Soup Cans\u00a0is a work of art consisting of 32 canvases, each painted with a Campbell's Soup can.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c428", "question": "Where in the body will you find your aqueous humour?", "answer": "Eye", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6010c8df0775fa611bce67e5", "question": "The French term \"bon voyage\" literally translates to what?", "answer": "Good voyage -- Bon voyage is sometimes casually used as a stand-in for \"goodbye\".", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b3230fbbf195a31e15d7380", "question": "Which gland is enlarged in the condition known as \"goitre\"?", "answer": "The Thyroid gland", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5f9f4100af848b908361b86e", "question": "What is the opening line of Rick Astley's \"Never Gonna Give You Up\" song?", "answer": "We're no strangers to love", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f49", "question": "Both of TV's \"Gilmore Girls\" have what first name?", "answer": "Lorelei", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59029d5acad1ec93f27df74c", "question": "Where did Thomas Lipton open his first grocery store?", "answer": "Glasgow, Scotland", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b064", "question": "The \"CSS Hunley\" was the first of what type of vessel to sink an enemy ship?", "answer": "Submarine", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe73812eec85e375820b261", "question": "Which US state has the largest aquifer?", "answer": "Nebraska", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd87", "question": "What type of animal is the Japanese monster, Kumonga?", "answer": "Spider", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5e72cf19d0874f1a5e2d1c29", "question": "How much liquid can be placed in a 10 gallon hat?", "answer": "3/4 of a gallon (US)", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399e4", "question": "What actor played Ross and Monica\u2019s father, Jack, on the TV show \"Friends\"?", "answer": "Elliot Gould", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5d2", "question": "Which desert is the driest on earth?", "answer": "Atacama", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b699245e762b54eb9be9420", "question": "What mother-daughter \"scream queen\" duo starred in the 1998 film \"Halloween H20: 20 Years Later\"?", "answer": "Jamie Lee Curtis and Janet Leigh", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea33a3ff048f679a45aaf0", "question": "What do you call a group of toads?", "answer": "A knot", "category": "science"}, {"id": "60078b300eee65b76b9f2664", "question": "Which U.S. president had a home called The Hermitage?", "answer": "Andrew Jackson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd8210cd0de9af39e9d46a2", "question": "What year did the War of 1812 end?", "answer": "1815", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffcfd749dc5ec6cd98a8324", "question": "What famous literary character offers this sage advice: \"Neither a borrower nor a lender be\"?", "answer": "Polonius (In\u00a0\"Hamlet\"\u00a0(Act I, Scene III),\u00a0he offers the sage advice to his son Laertes who is about to leave home.)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2ae", "question": "Which effect makes the average Earth's temperature around 15 degrees centigrade?", "answer": "The greenhouse effect", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c745", "question": "In what organ of the human body is the hippocampus?", "answer": "The brain", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b035", "question": "In what decade did North and South Korea declare themselves sovereign from each other?", "answer": "1940s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339808", "question": "What nationality is Celine Dion?", "answer": "Canadian", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2b6", "question": "What is lighter, gasoline or water?", "answer": "Gasoline", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a52", "question": "What musical instrument's name means \"bells playing\" in German?", "answer": "Glockenspiel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca06", "question": "What is the Shaddock a variety of?", "answer": "Citrus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a085", "question": "What was Kirk Douglas' birth name?", "answer": "Issur Danielovitch", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e6b", "question": "Who played the blind character in the movie \"Scent of a Woman\"?", "answer": "Al Pacino", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60062ba7c9d816e292245c22", "question": "What is the name of Captain Ahab's ship?", "answer": "The Pequod", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c49b", "question": "Bubble wrap was invented accidentally by researchers who were trying to develop a new type of what?", "answer": "A 3-dimensional wallpaper", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe65ed21f3c0ead6880d630", "question": "What does the French dessert B\u00fbche de No\u00ebl represent?", "answer": "Yule log", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d3f", "question": "In Italian, the Mona Lisa is called what?", "answer": "La Giocondo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fede60a6ce05a3942286df4", "question": "On what avenue does the traditional New York City Easter Parade and Bonnet Festival take place?", "answer": "Fifth Avenue", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597cd690e347d002c297e4bb", "question": "Collectively, what name is given to the first ten of the amendments to the United States Constitution?", "answer": "The Bill of Rights", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015fc46fe83fe1f2a824c3f", "question": "The Sykes-Picot agreement of 1916 divided up the Middle East with new boundaries that benefited which two global powers?", "answer": "Britain and France", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a592", "question": "Carson City is the capital of which US state?", "answer": "Nevada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6008e036f4f3bc4a292f8630", "question": "Who said, \"No one can make you feel inferior without your consent\"?", "answer": "Eleanor Roosevelt (The wife of President Franklin Roosevelt was a political force in her own right.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a56f", "question": "Which US state has shoreline along the Gulf of Mexico and the Atlantic Ocean?", "answer": "Florida", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c963", "question": "Parr, Smolt and Grilse are lifecycle stages for what fish?", "answer": "Salmon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac6a", "question": "What name was Haitian dictator Francois Duvalier better known by?", "answer": "Papa Doc", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9f7", "question": "What is the name of Nintendo's first video game console?", "answer": "Color TV Game", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1be", "question": "Lesley Hornby became more famous as who?", "answer": "Twiggy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4dd7306d333868d34d702", "question": "Ayatollah Khomeini called for a fatwa on which author of 1988's \"The Satanic Verses\"?", "answer": "Salman Rushdie", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a55c", "question": "What city is nicknamed the \"Big Apple\"?", "answer": "New York City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abed", "question": "Kiev is the capital of which European country?", "answer": "Ukraine", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd66b3fa5bfecdd737e0883", "question": "What is the name of a full moon that occurs in January?", "answer": "Wolf moon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8fbce01dd7bf43be5e855", "question": "Who said, \"Imagination is more important than knowledge\"?", "answer": "Albert Einstein", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c64", "question": "What Stephen King novel features an evil clown named Pennywise?", "answer": "It", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c616", "question": "What is the process called where a plant makes its food?", "answer": "Photosynthesis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2b3", "question": "In what ship's 1945 sinking were there as many as eighty sailors eaten by whitetip sharks?", "answer": "The USS Indianapolis", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59067b19ff9c0647b50a8060", "question": "The Gotthard Base Tunnel, which opened on June 1, 2016, is located in which country?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133926f", "question": "How much does the Academy Award statue weigh?", "answer": "8.5 pounds", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea780cff048f679a45abd2", "question": "During what era did mammals rule?", "answer": "Cenozoic", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe36ce40ada16518afdc03e", "question": "What car company makes the Econoline van", "answer": "Ford", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bff3", "question": "What is the correct name for a virgin cow?", "answer": "Heifer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133964d", "question": "What kind of animal is the title character in the 2003 movie \"Finding Nemo\"?", "answer": "Clownfish", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c761", "question": "Mycology is the study of what?", "answer": "Fungi", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fec8b3bec223966ae8f8838", "question": "Prior to Brooks taking his life, what does he carve on the wall in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "\"Brooks was here.\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bde", "question": "Which fictional criminal has a sidekick called Bunny?", "answer": "Raffles", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339689", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is the name of Mr. Burns' stuffed bear?", "answer": "Bobo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8f21d01dd7bf43be5e80c", "question": "How do you know cheese curds are fresh?", "answer": "They squeak", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fc2f7d4cee580c7f8fd1e5f", "question": "What does the word \"Radar\" stand for?", "answer": "RAdio Detection And Ranging", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffb5ed75dad637d903c8826", "question": "What World Heritage Site's name translates to \"holy wisdom\"?", "answer": "Hagia Sophia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59e3f7405cb9e8bda682136e", "question": "What year was the wreck of the Titanic discovered?", "answer": "1985", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a25f", "question": "What is Jane Fonda's middle name?", "answer": "Seymour", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ab969186faa38a764be520", "question": "What company did Mercedes-Benz partner with to develop the Smart car?", "answer": "Swatch", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4cb", "question": "Which New England state doesn't border the Atlantic Ocean?", "answer": "Vermont", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59db76d20ab2c8f322317fe7", "question": "In which ocean or sea are the Seychelles?", "answer": "Indian Ocean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e5d", "question": "What literary work inspired Sting's \"Moon Over Bourbon Street\" song?", "answer": "Interview with a Vampire", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7f3", "question": "What animal is \"Artemia salina\"?", "answer": "Brine shrimp", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3c8", "question": "Who is credited with the discovery of penicillin?", "answer": "Alexander Fleming", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b727", "question": "Christmas Seals are sponsored by what non-profit organization?", "answer": "The Lung Association", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339119", "question": "Who is the protagonist of H. G. Wells' \"The Island of Doctor Moreau\"?", "answer": "Edward Prendick", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5909cd15bb53d1af658864e6", "question": "How many times does the word \"jingle\" appear in the first verse of \"Jingle Bells\"?", "answer": "Three", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339331", "question": "What western drama series told the story of Pat Garrett and Billy the Kid?", "answer": "The Tall Man", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a77a", "question": "What city serves as the capital of Northern Ireland?", "answer": "Belfast", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8f5", "question": "What is an external agent that alters foetal development is called?", "answer": "Teratogen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe65825ae7e414034b5aee8", "question": "Who was the husband of the female Judge Deborah in the Bible?", "answer": "Lapidoth", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "594a63192ebb971c1417fb97", "question": "What year did the \"Turbot War\" fishing dispute end?", "answer": "1996", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59067ce0ff9c0647b50a8070", "question": "What is the name of the sixth expansion to the World of Warcraft game universe?", "answer": "World of Warcraft: Legion", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5b9", "question": "What is the difference between caskets and coffins?", "answer": "Coffins have six sides while caskets only four", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a434", "question": "Which tribes are native to New Zealand?", "answer": "Maori", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c189", "question": "Who was born Mark Feld?", "answer": "Marc Bolan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bab", "question": "Which book begins with the words \"The scent and smoke and sweat of a casino are nauseating at three in the morning\"?", "answer": "Casino Royale", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9be", "question": "What is the name of the frog companion that you find in Donkey Kong Country?", "answer": "Winky", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be93", "question": "What company opened its first Italian eatery at Brooklyn's Kings Plaza Shopping Center in 1967?", "answer": "Sbarro", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe773bceec85e375820b30c", "question": "How many \"emirates\" make up the United Arab Emirates?", "answer": "Seven", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338948", "question": "Which author hosted a 1960 fishing competition that Fidel Castro won?", "answer": "Ernest Hemmingway", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59636bc0967692ea851899a6", "question": "Which two signers of the \"Declaration of Independence\" who later became US Presidents, died on July 4, 1826?", "answer": "John Adams and Thomas Jefferson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fed2598ec223966ae8f8907", "question": "A \"foo fighter\", upon which the famous 1990's band is named, is a term derived from which line of professionals?", "answer": "Aircraft Pilots", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfe4", "question": "What is nephophobia the fear of?", "answer": "Clouds", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339785", "question": "What was Sam Malone's nickname on the TV show \"Cheers\"?", "answer": "Mayday", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be1a", "question": "What word did the University of Hawaii Warriors drop from their team name in 2001?", "answer": "Rainbow", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad4f", "question": "How many openings were there in the Berlin Wall?", "answer": "Two", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe3ecf58b5801b8f54a7faf", "question": "Peleus and Thetis were the parents of what famed warrior?", "answer": "Achilles", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b595", "question": "How many dice are there in the game of \"Boggle\"?", "answer": "Sixteen", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd6a1936c0f9723ab15cb3b", "question": "Which Roman emperor's name meant \"little boots\"?", "answer": "Caligula", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394a9", "question": "Who starred as John Drake in the TV show \"Secret Agent\"?", "answer": "Patrick McGoohan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f98", "question": "What character from a pop song wears electric boots and a mohair suit?", "answer": "Bennie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7cfdf877e98cb97778a56", "question": "What is the southern most city in the contiguous U.S.?", "answer": "Key West", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fdfbfbd003d27d341092bd8", "question": "How much lower does the Dead Sea get every year?", "answer": "One meter", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd81b26d0de9af39e9d4675", "question": "What was the capital city of the Aztec Empire?", "answer": "Tenochtitlan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c46a", "question": "What does the medical acronym PET stand for?", "answer": "Positron Emission Tomography", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d31", "question": "In the 1956 western, what actress are The Searchers searching for?", "answer": "Natalie Wood", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2a6", "question": "What nation was led by Alexander the Great?", "answer": "Macedon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b392", "question": "In what country did the \"Sepoy Mutiny\" occur?", "answer": "India", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe738d1eec85e375820b268", "question": "In which country do people traditionally eat at KFC for Christmas?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7354beec85e375820b248", "question": "Who said, \u201cThere are a terrible lot of lies going about the world, and the worst of it is that half of them are true.\"?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58f5675e33a95c66dc4fe76a", "question": "Scoleciphobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Worms", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d39", "question": "Who's responsible for \"The Ballad of A Well-Known Gun\"?", "answer": "Elton John", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3d4", "question": "What part of the eye is damaged by glaucoma?", "answer": "The optic nerve", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399ff", "question": "Who won an Oscar for his role as a drill sergeant in the movie \"An Officer and a  Gentleman\"?", "answer": "Louis Gossett Jr.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd9b", "question": "What was first marketed with hillbilly-themed advertising, since its name is an euphemism for moonshine?", "answer": "Mountain Dew", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601219dd63c99d48cd169afc", "question": "What is a haboob?", "answer": "A type of sand storm", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bdb", "question": "Which author won the Booker Prize 1986 for the novel \"The Old Devils\"?", "answer": "Kingsley Amis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a34f", "question": "What is the second largest country in the World?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59e6ba74fb6c85e9e634ff51", "question": "What branch of mathematics is named for the Latin for \"small pebble\"?", "answer": "Calculus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e8", "question": "What does M.C. stand for in M.C. Escher's name?", "answer": "Maurits Cornelis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a618", "question": "The underground lake, The Lost Sea, is located in which US state's Craighead Caverns?", "answer": "Tennessee", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5e9", "question": "The first American blood bank was established in 1937 in which city?", "answer": "Chicago", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d0c", "question": "What movie's first sequel featured the subtitle \"Road Warrior\"?", "answer": "Mad Max", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133962e", "question": "What TV character sings the song \"Smelly Cat\"?", "answer": "Phoebe Buffay", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6014c4c3fbde8045e48466a1", "question": "What is the function of the skin patches (warts) on a warthog's face?", "answer": "Protection during fights -- Like many animals, male warthogs battle for dominance during mating season.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc5f", "question": "What material are jeans made of?", "answer": "Cotton", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0d4", "question": "In the song where was \"The House of the Rising Sun\" located?", "answer": "New Orleans", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c831", "question": "The \"Wandering\" species of what bird has the longest wingspan in nature?", "answer": "Albatross", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe4b73e06d333868d34d6f8", "question": "Who was the British Navy Minister during World War I?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7f8", "question": "Into what body of water does the Danube River empty?", "answer": "The Black Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59f9bb30364247bf200fb8a1", "question": "Which decade did the Bee Gees release the album \"Trafalgar\"?", "answer": "1970s", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaa6", "question": "What is the easternmost state in the contiguous US?", "answer": "Maine", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff51717ff04d658268c92f8", "question": "What was Cleopatra's ethnicity?", "answer": "Despite being born in Egypt, Cleopatra's ancestral roots are planted in Macedonian Greece.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca53", "question": "The rate of change of velocity is known as what?", "answer": "Acceleration", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b358a265db0d66a186cb551", "question": "Minsk is the capital of which European country?", "answer": "Belarus", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acec", "question": "What Canadian city boasts the world's richest rodeo that was first staged in 1912?", "answer": "Calgary", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba49", "question": "During what decade was the first Super Bowl played?", "answer": "1960s", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395f8", "question": "Which actress played Forrest Gump's mom?", "answer": "Sally Field", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6018bb53d96d05b23b28164d", "question": "Rome was founded in which year?", "answer": "753 B.C.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133995d", "question": "What was Indiana Jones\u2019 real first name?", "answer": "Henry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ed8", "question": "What pieces of fruit contain three princesses in Sergei Prokofiev's most famous opera?", "answer": "Oranges", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fefbe546ce05a3942286eed", "question": "Which actor had a role in the Hannibal Lector films \"Manhunter,\" \"Silence of the Lambs,\" \"Hannibal\" and \"Red Dragon\"?", "answer": "Frankie Faison", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe529471bf59ab7d2e38101", "question": "What food or beverage can be made inside all British tanks?", "answer": "Tea", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5bfe0058b668d7dfe168b5c1", "question": "How would the number 10 be expressed in binary notation?", "answer": "1010", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a947", "question": "What nation removed the prefix \"Trans\" from before its name in June 1949?", "answer": "Jordan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339760", "question": "How much of the population has survived by 2035 in Twelve Monkeys? 1, 5 or 10 percent?", "answer": "1 percent", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca0d", "question": "Which island is the Dodo originally from?", "answer": "Mauritus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59049b64cf93664eb104869f", "question": "Which producer on the TV show \"Lost\" co-created the comic book series \"Y: The Last Man\"?", "answer": "Brian K. Vaughan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a9e95017ccba3ffe45786db", "question": "Which computer scientist was largely responsible for the design of \"FLOW-MATIC\", the first English-like data processing language?", "answer": "Grace Hopper", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe6aa4f20565ad31a57c815", "question": "The Anaconda Plan was associated to which war?", "answer": "The American Civil War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fedda0b6ce05a3942286d7f", "question": "Who replaced Richard Harris as Dumbledore in the Harry Potter films?", "answer": "Michael Gambon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e31", "question": "In the nursery rhyme \"This Little Piggy\", what meat did the third little piggy eat?", "answer": "Roast beef", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "593c4b07b8198b9a2b077960", "question": "Who starred opposite Jack Nicholson in the film \"As Good as It Gets\"?", "answer": "Helen Hunt", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6000ee019a72b906b34e3cf3", "question": "Which part of the body is affected by blepharitis?", "answer": "Eyelids", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338be2", "question": "Ludwig van Beethoven and Francisco Goya both suffered from what ailment?", "answer": "Deafness", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c24f", "question": "What do you call the feeling of having experienced something before?", "answer": "Deja vu", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7c5c2877e98cb977789b3", "question": "The \"Khyber Pass\" connects what two countries?", "answer": "Afghanistan and Pakistan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cf0", "question": "In what Edgar Allen Poe poem does the narrator lament the loss of his lover, Lenore?", "answer": "The Raven", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e5b", "question": "Who provided the original voice for Buzz Lightyear?", "answer": "Tim Allen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7eb", "question": "What does a chef do with a mandoline?", "answer": "Slice", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad96", "question": "Ferdinand Marcos and Corazon Aquino have both been Presidents of which country?", "answer": "Philippines", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339489", "question": "Who played the warden in the movie \"Natural Born Killers\"?", "answer": "Tommy Lee Jones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6a66320565ad31a57c7d8", "question": "From what island did the Enola Gay leave on its flight to drop the atomic bomb on Hiroshima?", "answer": "Tinian", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390fd", "question": "What year did Frederick Forsyth publish the novel \"The Fist of God\"?", "answer": "1994", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9ca", "question": "Which Apollo mission carried Neil Armstrong and his team to the Moon?\u00a0", "answer": "Apollo 11", "category": "science"}, {"id": "601b4a1a49076251badbeaaf", "question": "Who was the first leader of the Republic of Texas?", "answer": "Sam Houston -- He later became one of Texas's first senators and then the state's governor.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab2e", "question": "Which ocean is Fiji located in?", "answer": "Pacific", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe767e7eec85e375820b29a", "question": "What is the world's widest river?", "answer": "Amazon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adc7", "question": "What was the name of the 1783 treaty that formally ended the American Revolutionary War?", "answer": "The Treaty of Paris", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3ff", "question": "What is the name of the largest known satellite of Pluto?", "answer": "Charon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339685", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", who normally drives Springfield Elementary's school bus?", "answer": "Otto", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a90", "question": "Who provides James Bond with his gadgets?", "answer": "Q", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339723", "question": "Bruce Springsteen was given what nickname?", "answer": "The Boss", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb27", "question": "What fast food chain formerly used the ad slogan, \"Fresh-Hot-Small-Square\"?", "answer": "Krystal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339475", "question": "What was the name of the store Seymour works at in the movie \"One Hour Photo\"?", "answer": "SavMart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59db75270ab2c8f322317fe5", "question": "Peridot is which month's birthstone?", "answer": "August", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f43", "question": "Who created the character of Fozzie Bear?", "answer": "Jim Henson", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5febd4ca7e83c707845b2160", "question": "In the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\", which character had his hands replaced by the director, Frank Darabont, as insert shot?", "answer": "Andy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c342", "question": "What plant when ingested (in small quantities) can make the oil of your skin poisonous?", "answer": "Oleander", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a187", "question": "In the cartoon \"Wacky Races\", who drove the Compact Pussycat?", "answer": "Penelope Pitstop", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adc3", "question": "Which country was the scene of the Mau Mau rebellion in the 1950s?", "answer": "Kenya", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fede2266ce05a3942286dcd", "question": "\"Santa Baby\" contributed to which singer\u2019s fame?", "answer": "Eartha Kitt", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe1efcf145fb2946670738e", "question": "What is the Japanese art of flower arrangement called?", "answer": "Ikebana", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a635", "question": "The Silicon Valley is located in what California valley?", "answer": "Santa Clara Valley", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8c6", "question": "What is a group of owls called?", "answer": "A parliament", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad8c", "question": "Where was the Salvation Army's Christmas collection kettle first introduced?", "answer": "San Francisco", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a162c2ef01ec323f849172e", "question": "Who was the legendary front man for the band Roxy Music?", "answer": "Bryan Ferry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad8a", "question": "How long did Pope John Paul I serve?", "answer": "33 days", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fecdcdcec223966ae8f88f9", "question": "What actor played the role of Margaret White in the 2013 film \"Carrie\"?", "answer": "Julianne Moore", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4ba949076251badbeac6", "question": "The first North American\u00a0English seasonal camp was founded where?", "answer": "St. John's, Newfoundland -- In 1583, Sir\u00a0Humphrey Gilbert, by the\u00a0royal prerogative\u00a0of\u00a0Queen Elizabeth I, founded\u00a0St. John's.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b53c", "question": "What word in the English language with three consecutive sets of double letters?", "answer": "Bookkeeper", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be73", "question": "What is LP Field also known as?", "answer": "The Woodshed", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5f4", "question": "Which US state is known as the \u201cLand of Enchantment\u201d?", "answer": "New Mexico", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133946a", "question": "In what decade does the movie \"Girl, Interrupted\" take place?", "answer": "1960s", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea4810ff048f679a45abae", "question": "What is the first priority in a trauma code?", "answer": "Airway", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6000ed209a72b906b34e3ce9", "question": "Fissures, vents and plugs are all associated with which geological feature?", "answer": "Volcano", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a3a", "question": "What type of animal was Bambi's friend Flower?", "answer": "Skunk", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396c9", "question": "The TV show \"Frasier\" is based in what US city?", "answer": "Seattle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1b0", "question": "Which music genre lilterally means \"new trend\" in Portuguese?", "answer": "Bossa Nova", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb30", "question": "What is your occupation if you are sometimes referred to as an apiarist?", "answer": "Beekeeper", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acf2", "question": "What was the official name for the World War II evacuation of Dunkirk?", "answer": "Operation Dynamo", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339abd", "question": "Who played the Vice-President of the US in the 1997 movie \"Air Force One\"?", "answer": "Glenn Close", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339223", "question": "What is the name of Futurama's first episode aired in 1999?", "answer": "Space Pilot 3000", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9f2", "question": "Metamorphic, sedimentary, and igneous are types of what?", "answer": "Rocks", "category": "science"}, {"id": "601b4bc649076251badbeac8", "question": "What was U.S. President Woodrow Wilson's reelection campaign slogan in 1916?", "answer": "\"He Kept Us Out of War\" -- Despite the slogan, he asked Congress to declare war in 1917.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c90d", "question": "What is the young offspring of the Antelope called?", "answer": "Calf", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfbc", "question": "If you suffer from ailurophobia what are you afraid of?", "answer": "Cats", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa6d", "question": "Liege municipality is located in which country?", "answer": "Belgium", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339445", "question": "What was the name of Tom Hanks' character in the movie \"Cast Away\"?", "answer": "Chuck Noland", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fb085dacf631c2414a13b4f", "question": "In the TV show \"Friends\", what is Chandler\u2019s middle name?", "answer": "Muriel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b15c", "question": "Who was awarded the Nobel Peace Prize in 1979?", "answer": "Mother Teresa", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaeb", "question": "Which city is the capital of Tuscany?", "answer": "Florence", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be6b", "question": "What is Dodger Stadium also known as?", "answer": "Chavez Ravine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339290", "question": "On the TV show \"Lost\", what group conducts scientific experiments on the island?", "answer": "Dharma Initiative", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59db787d0ab2c8f322317ff3", "question": "What is the capital of Nova Scotia?", "answer": "Halifax", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe6ab2f20565ad31a57c825", "question": "Who said, \"Books give a soul to the universe, wings to the mind, flight to the imagination, and life to everything\"?", "answer": "Plato", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a958", "question": "Which European country replaced the Pound with the Euro?", "answer": "Ireland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339400", "question": "Who was the name of Ray Liotta's character in the 1990 movie \"Goodfellas\"?", "answer": "Henry Hill", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa14", "question": "South Africa's Robben Island takes its name from which creatures?", "answer": "Seals", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58f166fbf7c52aae91cc07b4", "question": "Which is the largest of Neptune's moons?", "answer": "Triton", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391dd", "question": "Who played Mr. Orange in the movie \"Reservoir Dogs\"?", "answer": "Tim Roth", "category": "entertainment"}]